A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 9287-11774 FA739D
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Special Committee for Program Policy Review in the 1960s Program Submission Concerning Future Program Activities, The Ford Foundation Special Committee, 1962 Spring (Reports 011158)
- The Ford Foundation in the 1960s, Statement of the Board of Trustees on Policies, Programs, and Operations (Reports 011159), 1962
- The Role of the Foundation in American Society. W. McNeil Lowry, Director, Program in Humanities and the Arts, The Ford Foundation, The Nassau Club, Princeton (Reports 011160), 1958; Lowry, W. McNeil (Wilson McNeil), 1913-
- Address by John J. McCloy, United States Military Academy, West Point, New York, 1961 December 6 (Reports 011161), McCloy, John J. (John Jay), 1895-1989
- The Road to Peace, An Address by John J. McCloy, Counsel, Milbank, Tweed, Hope and Hadley, New York, 1961 November 29 (Reports 011162), McCloy, John J. (John Jay), 1895-1989
- Public Affairs Program (Reports 011163), 1958 (Box 448)
  32 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Law and the social sciences -- United States; Sociological jurisprudence
- Indicators for understanding: a profile of metro Chicago's immigrant community. (Reports 011164), 1995; Latino Institute (Chicago, Ill.); Northern Illinois University. Office for Social Policy Research; Chicago Community Trust (Box 448)
  52 p.: ill.; 28 cm.
  Emigration and immigration -- Chicago (Ill.) -- Statistics; Emigration and immigration -- Illinois -- Statistics; Ethnic groups -- Chicago (Ill.) -- Statistics; Ethnic groups -- Illinois -- Statistics; Latino Institute (Chicago, Ill.); Northern Illinois University. Office for Social Policy Research; Chicago Community Trust; Latino Institute (Chicago, Ill.)
- The Ford Foundation in the United Arab Republic: program proposals for the fiscal year 1963 (Reports 011165) (Box 448)
- The Ford Foundation in the United Arab Republic: program proposals for the fiscal year 1962 (Reports 011166) (Box 448)
- Professional service in support of special purpose housing, November 4 (Reports 011167), 1963; Faust, Clarence H. (Clarence Henry), 1901-1975 (Box 448)
  5 p. - 28 cm.
  Housing; Housing -- Endowments
- Continued support of selected experimental programs in urban research, education and extension (Reports 011168), 1963; Faust, Clarence H. (Clarence Henry), 1901-1975 (Box 448)
  5 p. + attachments: tables -- 28 cm.
  Cities and towns -- Research -- United States; Community development, Urban -- United States; Education, Urban -- United States; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation
- Improving the administration of justice (Reports 011169), 1962; Brown, Dyke (Box 448)
  Criminal Justice, Administration of -- United States
- The Ford Foundation Program in Argentina and Chile, Sept. (Reports 011170), 1963; Wilhelm, Harry E.; Atwater, Verne S. (Box 448)
  Philanthropy -- Argentina; Philanthropy -- Chile; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program
- A review of political, administrative and economic trends in India and Nepal (Reports 011171), 1961; Ensminger, Douglas, 1910-1989 (Box 448)
  16 leaves + attachments: ill., graphs, tables -- 28 cm.
  Technical assistance -- India; Endowments -- India -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. South and Southeast Asia
- The Ford Foundation's program in Argentina and Chile (Reports 011172), 1963 (Box 448)
  Technical assistance -- Argentina; Technical assistance -- Chile; Endowments -- Argentina -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Chile -- Evaluation
- The Ford Foundation in Pakistan Program review and status report (Reports 011173), 1961; Case, Harry L. (Harry Lawrence), 1907- (Box 448)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Pakistan; Ford Foundation. South and Southeast Asia
- Ford Foundation supported activities in Indonesia: status report (Reports 011174), 1961 (Box 448)
  Technical assistance -- Indonesia; Endowments -- Indonesia -- Evaluation
- Special education program for the Arab states (Reports 011175), 1954; Egger, Rowland, 1908-1979 (Box 448)
- Research: analysis and review (Reports 011176), 1953; Swayzee, Cleon Oliphant, 1903-1990 (Box 448)
  Foreign study -- United States; Area studies -- United States; Ford Foundation. Overseas Training and Research
- Overseas Development Program: Pakistan: plans and estimates, January 1956 to (Reports 011177), Gant, George F. (Box 448)
  34 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Endowments -- India -- Finance; Endowments -- Pakistan -- Finance; Philanthropy -- Pakistan -- Finance; Philanthropy -- India -- Finance; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program
- How the Near East Program is planned (Reports 011178), 1956 (Box 448)
  Charity organization -- Middle East; Technical assistance -- Middle East; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation
- Budget and program review (Reports 011179), 1955; Egger, Rowland, 1908-1979 (Box 448)
  iii, 23 leaves: tables -- 28 cm.
  Technical assistance -- Middle East; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance
- Pakistan program projections and budget 1961-62 through 1965-66 (Reports 011180), 1962 (Box 448)
  26 leaves + attachments: tables -- 28 cm.
  Technical assistance -- Pakistan; Endowments -- Pakistan -- Evaluation; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance
- India Program budget for 1960-61 (Reports 011181), Ensminger, Douglas, 1910-1989 (Box 448)
  Analysis of current situation in India and description of existing and proposed projects.
  Subsidies -- India
- Near East Program summaries (Reports 011182), 1955; Egger, Rowland, 1908-1979 (Box 448)
  Letter to Kenneth R. Iverson, dated November 16, 1955.
  Technical assistance -- Middle East; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation
- Pakistan Program budget (Reports 011183), 1958; Culbertson, Robert E. (Box 448)
  Letter to George F. Gant, dated December 22, 1958.
  6 leaves + attachment -- 28 cm.
- Pakistan Program projection (Reports 011184), 1954; Klemme, Randall T. (Box 448)
  Letter to Kenneth R. Iverson, dated September 1, 1954.
- Pakistan Program projections (Reports 011185), 1955; Klemme, Randall T. (Box 448)
  Letter to Kenneth R. Iverson, dated January 11, 1955.
  36 leaves: tables -- 28 cm.
- India Program: memo (Reports 011186), 1954; Ensminger, Douglas, 1910-1989 (Box 448)
  Update of India program for 1954-1956 planning period.
- Pakistan Program problems (Reports 011187), 1958; Culbertson, Robert E. (Box 448)
  Letter to George F. Gant, dated August 30, 1958.
- Pakistan Program budget: your letter of April 12, 1960 (Reports 011188), Culbertson, Robert E. (Box 448)
  Letter to George F. Gant, dated April 26, 1960.
- India Program standard report. No. 1: status of active grants as of July 15 (Reports 011189), 1960 (Box 448)
  List of active grants by the India Field Office.
- Special Committee for Program Policy Review in the 1960s: proceedings (Reports 011190), 1962 (Box 450, Box 449)
  Notes on Sessions I-XII.
  4 v.: var. pag -- 28 cm.
- The role of the Foundation in American society: Princeton (Reports 011191), 1958; Lowry, W. McNeil (Wilson McNeil), 1913- (Box 450)
  Speech given at the Nassau Club in Princeton, N.J.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Social aspects; Philanthropy -- United States; Ford Foundation. Program in Humanities and Arts.
- Address: United States Military Academy, West Point, New York (Reports 011192), 1961; McCloy, John J. (John Jay), 1895-1989 (Box 450)
  Disarmament; Peace; Democracy; United States Military Academy
- Conversations and correspondence with American and international leaders and experts (Reports 011193), 1962
  [New York]: Ford Foundation, 1962.
  Ford Foundation's policy, program and operational directives for the 1960s: vol. III.
  International relations; Ford Foundation
- Directives and terms of reference for the 1960s (Reports 011193-001), 1962 (Box 450)
- Directives and terms of reference for the 1960s: Supporting materials - Volume I: Ford Foundation Program Evaluation (Reports 011193-002), 1962 (Box 450)
- Directives and terms of reference for the 1960s: Supporting materials - Volume II: Trustee and Staff Proposals for Ford Foundation Programs for the 1960s (Reports 011193-003), 1962 (Box 450)
- Directives and terms of reference for the 1960s: Supporting materials - Volume III: Conversations and Correspondence with American and International Leaders and Experts (Reports 011193-004), 1962 (Box 450)
- Directives and terms of reference for the 1960s: Supporting materials - Volume IV: Special Papers and Working Documents (Reports 011193-005), 1962 (Box 451)
- Rural poverty and resources (Reports 011194), 1984 (Box 451)
  New York worldwide actual FY 1984 and expected FY 1985 budget allocations. --p. [1].
  5 p. + attachments;tables -- 28 cm.
  Developing Country Programs: FY 1985 Program Reviews: New York, International Affairs
  Rural poor -- Developing countries; Rural development -- Developing countries; Agriculture -- Research -- Developing countries
- Changing emphases in the Ford Foundation's population work (Reports 011195), 1984 (Box 451)
  For discussion at the December 1984 Trustees' Meeting. -T.p.
  43 p.+ attachments: tables
  Population research -- Developing countries; Population assistance -- Developing countries; Birth control -- Developing countries
- Developing country programs: FY 1985 program reviews, New York: International Affairs (Reports 011196), 1984 (Box 451)
  Developing Countries Program/International Affairs
  11 p. + attachments: tables -- 28 cm.
  International relations; International economic relations; Security, International; Arms control
- Developing country programs: FY 1985 program reviews: Brazil (Reports 011197), 1984 (Box 451)
  39 leaves: tables -- 28 cm.
  Technical assistance -- Brazil; Endowments -- Brazil -- Evaluation
- Developing country programs: FY 1985 program reviews: China and other Asia (Reports 011198), 1984 (Box 451)
  Developing Countries Program/China
  Technical assistance -- China; Endowments -- China -- Evaluation
- Developing country programs: FY 1985 rapporteur notes (Reports 011199), 1984 (Box 451)
  This report contains ten program reviews by each of the program offices dealing with hers/his respective field in DCP.
  p. 53.
  Human rights and governance; International relations; Rural poverty and resourses; Urban poverty; Women
- U.S. foreign policy: discussion paper at the meeting of the Trustees' Human Rights, Governance and International Affairs Committee (Reports 011200), 1983 (Box 451)
  International Affairs/Human Rights and Governance
  p. 54.
  International relations -- United States
- Annual program status report: Pakistan, fiscal year (Reports 011202), 1973 (Box 451)
  Program reports, supplements, and budget projections for the year.
  Overseas Division/South and Southeast Asia;International Division/Asia and the Pacific
  07191366
  22 p. + appendices
  Philanthropy -- Pakistan
- The road to peace an address by (Reports 011203), 1961; McCloy, John J. (John Jay), 1895-1989 (Box 451)
  Disarmament; Peace; World politics
- The quality of the doctorate in schools of education: a final report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 011204), 1985; Brown, Laurence D.; Schneider, Barbara L. (Box 451)
  Urban Poverty program
  08450155
  Northwestern University
  [116] p.;28 cm.
  Doctor of education degree; Northwestern University (Evanston, Ill.)
- Conservation of manuscripts at Varendra Research Museum, Rajshahi: Final report including report on Dhaka University Library (Reports 011205), 1985; Kathpalia, Yash Pal (Box 451)
  Manuscripts -- Conservation and restoration; Varendra Research Museum
- An evaluation of two Ford Foundation grants: PA770-0093 and PA845-0643 (Reports 011206), 1985; Myers, Robert G.
  Education -- Colombia; Colombia Foundation for Higher Education.
- Modeling the environmental effects of forest management in a watershed: A multi-objective approach to forest management for developing countries (Reports 011207), 1981; Allen, Julia Coan, 1955- (Box 451)
  Forest management -- Developing countries
- Specification of rural electrification analysis (Reports 011208), 1981; Barnes, Douglas F. (Box 451)
- Innovation in political communication: the sound broadcasting of parliamentary proceedings (Reports 011209), 1978; Blumler, Jay G. (Box 451)
  United States and International Affairs Program
  L78-147.
  Communication in politics
- The intervention of television in British politics (Reports 011210), 1975; Blumler, Jay G. (Box 451)
  Television and politics -- Great Britain; Mass media -- Research -- Great Britain; Great Britain. Committee of Inquiry on the Future of Broadcasting
- The role of theory in uses and gratifications studies (Reports 011211), 1977; Blumler, Jay G. (Box 451)
  Mass media
- Agricultural production, distribution and consumption: An interim program document for agriculture and rural development in Brazil, 1978-1980 (Reports 011212), Forman, Shepard, 1938-; Saint, William Staver, 1944- (Box 452)
  L78-143
  Agriculture; Rural development -- Brazil
- Environmental training in developing countries: a report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 011213), 1980; Leonard, H. Jeffrey (Box 452)
  L80-86
  Ecology -- Developing countries
- Strategies to increase mathematics enrollments (Reports 011214), 1980; Lantz, Alma E. (Box 452)
  L80-131
  Women -- Education -- Mathematics
- Sex differences in mathematics (Reports 011215), 1980; Dougherty, Knowles; Herbert, Martin; Edenhart-Pepe, Michael; Small, Ava (Box 452)
- Services: A new look at the U.S. economy (Reports 011216), 1980; Stanback, Thomas M.; Bearse, Peter; Noyelle, Thierry J.; Karasek, Robert (Robert A.) (Box 452)
  L80-143
  iii, [154] leaves -- 28 cm.
- Sugar or alcohol?: a billion dollar Brazilian question (Reports 011217), 1980; Islam, M. Shafiqul (Mohammad Shafiqul), 1939- (Box 452)
  Alcohol as fuel -- Brazil
- Direct biomass combustion potentials for industrial and electric generation applications in LDCs (Reports 011218), 1981; Noll, Scott (Box 452)
  Biomass energy -- Developing countries; Power resources -- Developing countries -- Economic aspects; Energy consumption -- Developing countries; Agriculture and energy -- Developing countries
- Charcoal industry location and transport study (Reports 011219), 1981; Allen, Julia Coan, 1955- (Box 452)
  Fuel trade; Charcoal industry
- Industrial energy conservation in developing countries (Reports 011220), 1980; Janowski, John E., Jr. (Box 452)
  Energy conservation
- LDC coal production, importation and use: issues and strategies (Reports 011221), 1981; Noll, Scott (Box 452)
  Coal -- Sources
- Factors affecting the composition of energy supplies in developing countries (Reports 011222), 1980; Dunkerley, Joy (Box 452)
  L80-162
  Fuel trade -- Developing countries; Power sources -- Developing countries
- The education of women at Oberlin (Reports 011223), 1980; Goldsmid, Paula L. (Box 452)
  L80-131.
  Women -- Education
- Middle East and Africa agricultural and resources: Seminar (Reports 011224), 1980; Jones, David B. (Box 452)
  L80-7
  Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- Africa; Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- Middle East
- The growth of energy consumption and prices in the USA, FRG, France, and the UK, 1950-1979 (Reports 011225), 1980; Doblin, Claire P. (Box 452)
  81 p.
  Energy consumption
- Village network, phase I: a proposal to the Ford Foundation (Reports 011226), 1981; Martha Stuart Communications. (Box 452)
  L80-235.
  Video tapes in education; Martha Stuart Communications, Inc.
- Videotape as a development tool, 1972-1976 (Reports 011227), 1980; Martha Stuart Communications (Box 452)
  37 p. + appendix -- 28 cm.
  Are you listening
  Video tapes in education -- Developing countries; Social change -- Developing countries; Martha Stuart Communications, Inc.
- Report of the Videotape as a Development Tool Workshop held in Bamako, Mali from 26 May to 30 (Reports 011228), 1980; Martha Stuart Communications. (Box 453)
- Sarvodaya Shramadana Movement five year development plan (Reports 011229), 1980; Lanka Jatika Sarvodaya Shramadana Sangamaya (Box 453)
  L80-119
  [iv], 70 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Rural development -- Sri Lanka; Technical assistance -- Sri Lanka; Sarvodaya Shamadana Movement
- A field-initiated proposal for a one-semester comprehensive health education course utilizing successful educational technologies (Reports 011230), 1978; Sutherland, John E. (Box 453)
  L80-171.
  Health education
- Sutherland Learning Associates, Inc.: background information (Reports 011231), 1978; Sutherland Learning Associates (Box 453)
  Communication -- Education; Sutherland Learning Associates
- The Spirit of ANCSA Alaska Native Commission Overview Hearings (Reports 011232), 1985; Alaska Native Review Commission
  Transcript of proceedings and overviews of roundtable discussions.
  8400459
  14 v.: var. pag: tables -- 28 cm.
  Land tenure -- Alaska; Land tenure -- United States; Inuit -- Land tenure; Eskimos -- Land tenure; Indians of North America -- Land tenure; Alaska Native Review Commission; Inuit Circumpolar Conference - Alaska Regional Office, Inc.
- Transcript of Proceedings - Overview Roundtable Discussions, Volume I: The Spirit of ANCSA, February 27 (Reports 011232-001), 1984 (Box 453)
  08400459
  Inuit Circumpolar Conference - Alaska Regional Office, Inc.
  Land tenure -- Alaska; Land tenure -- United States; Inuit -- Land tenure; Eskimos -- Land tenure; Indians of North America -- Land tenure; Alaska Native Review Commission
- Transcript of Proceedings - Overview Roundtable Discussions, Volume II: The Spirit of ANCSA, February 28 (Reports 011232-002), 1984 (Box 453)
- Transcript of Proceedings - Overview Roundtable Discussions, Volume III: The Spirit of ANCSA, February 29 (Reports 011232-003), 1984 (Box 453)
- Transcript of Proceedings - Overview Roundtable Discussions, Volume IV: ANCSA Institutions and Legal Regimes, March 1 (Reports 011232-004), 1984 (Box 453)
- Transcript of Proceedings - Overview Roundtable Discussions, Volume V: ANCSA Institutions and Legal Regimes, March 2 (Reports 011232-005), 1984 (Box 453)
- Transcript of Proceedings - Overview Roundtable Discussions, Volume VI: U.S. National Policy, March 6 (Reports 011232-006), 1984 (Box 453)
- Transcript of Proceedings - Overview Roundtable Discussions, Volume VII: U.S. National Policy, March 7 (Reports 011232-007), 1984 (Box 454)
- Transcript of Proceedings - Overview Roundtable Discussions, Volume VIII: U.S. National Policy, March 8 (Reports 011232-008), 1984 (Box 454)
- Transcript of Proceedings - Overview Roundtable Discussions, Volume IX: U.S. National Policy, March 9 (Reports 011232-009), 1984 (Box 454)
- Transcript of Proceedings - Overview Roundtable Discussions, Volume X: International Overview, March 13 (Reports 011232-010), 1984 (Box 454)
- Transcript of Proceedings - Overview Roundtable Discussions, Volume XI: International Overview, March 14 (Reports 011232-011), 1984 (Box 454)
- Transcript of Proceedings - Overview Roundtable Discussions, Volume XII: International Overview, March 15 (Reports 011232-012), 1984 (Box 454)
- Transcript of Proceedings - Overview Roundtable Discussions, Volume XIII: International Overview, March 16 (Reports 011232-013), 1984 (Box 454)
- Transcript of Proceedings - Overview Roundtable Discussions, Volume XIV: Overview Papers, February 27 - March 16 (Reports 011232-014), 1984 (Box 454)
- Student data systems at four UCC top colleges (Reports 011233), 1986; Bensimon, Estela Mara (Box 455)
  Education, Higher -- Growth
- Data provided to the Ford Foundation baccalaureates subsequently receiving doctoral degrees between 1951-80 in American colleges and universities (Reports 011234), 1985; Davis-Van Atta, David (Box 455)
  [32] p.
- The social composition of American enlisted forces: 19th and 20th century images and realities, political dynamics, and questionable assumptions (Reports 011236), 1983; Berryman, Sue E., 1938- (Box 455)
  MCA838-980.
  xxv, 138 leaves: tables -- 28 cm.
  Military service, Voluntary -- United States; Political science -- United States
- League of Professional Theatre Training programs actor presentation, March 26-27 1983 and design portfolio review (Reports 011238), Bartow, Arthur (Box 455)
  Theaters -- United States; Actors -- United States; Acting -- Study and teaching -- United States; Performing arts -- United States; Ford Foundation. Program in Education and Arts
- Festival Latino in New York: New York Shakespeare Festival (Reports 011239), 1986; Pottlitzer, Joanne (Box 455)
  Arts -- Philanthropy -- New York (N.Y.); Ford Foundation information dissemination -- New York (N.Y.); Arts, Latin American -- New York (N.Y.)
- Final report of the first meeting of the group of experts on science and technology (Reports 011240), 1967; Organization of American States (Box 455)
  06790021
  Science -- International cooperation; Organization of American States
- Reunion panamericana sobre la ensenanza de posgrado en ingenieria (Reports 011241), 1967; Pan American Union. Secretaria General Organizacion de los Estados Americanos.; Ford Foundaton. Latin America and the Caribbean (Box 455)
  Report of conference held August 20-24, 1967 in Caracas, Venezuela.
  Fiscal Year 1967 supporting projects for Latin America and the Caribbean (conferences).
  Education, Higher -- Latin America -- Congresses; Higher education and state -- Latin America -- Congresses; Pan American Union. Secretaria General Organizacion de los Estados Americanos.; Ford Foundaton. Latin America and the Caribbean
- The Christian college in changing India (Reports 011242), 1967; Dickinson, Richard D. N., 1929-2008 (Box 455)
  PN64-28.
  210 p. + appendices: ill., graphs, tables -- 32 cm.
  Church colleges -- India; Universities and colleges -- India; Education, Higher -- Social aspects -- India; Higher education and state -- India; Ford Foundation. South and Southeast Asia
- High school curriculum study (Reports 011243), 1963; Portland Public Schools (Box 455)
  Final report.
  Education -- Teacher training; Education, Higher -- Growth; Portland Public Schools
- Project for family planning and population control in Egypt (Reports 011244), 1973; Arab Republic of Egypt Supreme Council for Family Planning. (Box 455)
  IRS72-171.
  Birth control -- Egypt; Arab Republic of Egypt Supreme Council for Family Planning.
- Report on visits to Malaysia, the Philippines, and Indonesia, Nov.-Dec. (Reports 011245), 1971; Schaller, Howard G. (Box 455)
  728-0982
  Educational planning -- Southeast Asia
- The social context of educational policy (Reports 011246), 1976; Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies. Education Program (Box 455)
  750-0285.
  Education; Educational sociology; Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies. Education Program
- Cable television: Opportunities and problems in local program origination (Reports 011247), 1970; Feldman, Nathaniel E., 1925- (Box 455)
  Cable television distribution and its impact on the television industry.
  699-0481
  Television -- Role of -- Social research -- United States
- A Guide to Resource Centers Serving Children: Child survival/Fair Start Program (Reports 011248), 1985; So, Anthony D. (Box 456)
  An overview of national level resource centers in various areas of children's services.
  Child health services
- Meeting the AIDS challenge: opportunities for action and intervention (Reports 011249), 1987; Consultants Group on A.I.D.S. Policy. (Box 456)
  AIDS (Disease)
- Education and training for public policy-making and decisionmaking: Yale University (Reports 011250), 1971; Fleishman, Joel L. (Box 456)
  National Affairs/Social Development
  73-114.
  Education -- Public service
- Demonstration project in family planning Seyeda Zeina district, Cairo (Reports 011251), 1975; Assaad, Marie (Box 456)
  Study of clinic personnel & training needs;preliminary experiments with the training of social workers.